<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Ginger Geek</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2022-07-18T09:29:11-05:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Lee Calcote</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talk - Service Meshes, but at what cost]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2019/10/service-meshes-but-at-what-cost/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/service-meshes-but-at-what-cost</id>
  <published>2019-10-04T05:10:15-05:00</published>
  <updated>2019-10-04T05:10:15-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;As you learn of the architecture and value provided by service meshes, you’re intrigued and initially impressed. Upon reflection, you, like many others think: &lt;font style=&quot;color:grey;position:inline;&quot;&gt;“I see the value, but what overhead does being on the mesh incur?” &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complicating the answer is the fact that there are over 10 service meshes projects to choose from. While this presentation does not take an in-depth look at the&lt;a href=&quot;https://layer5.io/landscape&quot;&gt; landscape of service meshes&lt;/a&gt;, it does introduce &lt;a href=&quot;https://layer5.io/meshery&quot;&gt;Meshery&lt;/a&gt; as a utility for both benchmarking service mesh performance and provides a playground for familiarizing with the various features of different service meshes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/key/3PGWiGNg12FP8O&quot; width=&quot;595&quot; height=&quot;485&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; style=&quot;border:1px solid #CCC; border-width:1px; margin-bottom:5px; max-width: 100%;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;margin-bottom:5px&quot;&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;//www.slideshare.net/leecalcote/service-meshes-but-at-what-cost&quot; title=&quot;Service Meshes, but at what cost?&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Service Meshes, but at what cost?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.slideshare.net/leecalcote&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lee Calcote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk was delivered at &lt;a href=&quot;https://servicemeshday.com&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;Service Mesh Day 2019&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;./assets/Meshery-Service-Mesh-Day-2019.pdf&quot;&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Meshery - Service Mesh Day 2019&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;button&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;./assets/Meshery-Service-Mesh-Day-2019.pdf&quot; download=&quot;Meshery Service Mesh Day 2019&quot;&gt; Download &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/button&gt;
&lt;!-- /wp:file --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2019/10/service-meshes-but-at-what-cost/&quot;&gt;Talk - Service Meshes, but at what cost&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on October 04, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to establish an open source program office]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/how-to-establish-an-open-source-program-office" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/how-to-establish-an-open-source-program-office</id>
  <published>2018-12-18T06:41:15-06:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-18T06:41:15-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;In many companies, open source programs start informally with a group of diligent engineers and a few legal people. The ad-hoc group soon realizes it needs a more formal program to scale to address the litany of important issues and achieve specific business goals. With such an office in place, businesses can establish and execute on their open source strategies in clear terms, giving their leaders, developers, marketers, and other staff the tools they need to make open source a success within their operations. In this talk, I discussed:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul type=&quot;disc&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why to create an open source program office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The role of the open source program office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source programs at prominent technology companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to establish an open source office.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Program structure and management roles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Setting policy, processes and goals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measuring and monitoring success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at InnoTech Austin 2018. Slides below &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-innotech-austin-2018-establishing-an-open-source-office.html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; style=&quot;display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-innotech-austin-2018-establishing-an-open-source-office.html&quot;&gt;open slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/12/how-to-establish-an-open-source-program-office&quot;&gt;How to establish an open source program office&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 18, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talk - Linux Containers 101 – from engines to orchestrators]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/linux-containers-101-from-containers-to-orchestrators" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/linux-containers-101-from-containers-to-orchestrators</id>
  <published>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at DeveloperWeek Austin 2018 as an introduction to the concept of Docker containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-developerweek-austin-2018-linux-containers-101&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; style=&quot;display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-developerweek-austin-2018-linux-containers-101&quot;&gt;open slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/12/linux-containers-101-from-containers-to-orchestrators&quot;&gt;Talk - Linux Containers 101 – from engines to orchestrators&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 08, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What it means to be Cloud Native]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/what-it-means-to-be-cloud-native/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/what-it-means-to-be-cloud-native</id>
  <published>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This talk was presented at InnoTech San Antonio 2018 as a perspective of what it means to be Cloud Native &amp;#8211; from containers to functions. See the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/11/cloud-native-evolution.gif&quot;&gt;full-size&lt;/a&gt; animated gif.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;
&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot; lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;Preparing for a talk on &amp;#8220;Establishing an Open Source Program Office&amp;#8221; for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/INNOTECHAustin?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;@INNOTECHAustin&lt;/a&gt; this week has me looking back at last year&amp;#8217;s presentation &amp;#8211; &amp;#8220;What It Means to be Cloud Native?&amp;#8221; The answer is cross-cutting&amp;#8230; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Z9hTZVVsVj&quot;&gt;https://t.co/Z9hTZVVsVj&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/2w1lRCZxD2&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/2w1lRCZxD2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Lee Calcote (@lcalcote) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lcalcote/status/1046744435248254976?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;October 1, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot; type=&quot;852ae190fb4b7336cfaf374d-text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-innotech-san-antonio-2018-what-it-means-to-be-cloud-native.html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; style=&quot;display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/04/what-it-means-to-be-cloud-native/&quot;&gt;What it means to be Cloud Native&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 08, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Innovate Summit 2017 - State of Serverless & the CNCF]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2017/12/innovate-summit-2017-state-of-serverless-the-cncf/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/innovate-summit-2017-state-of-serverless-the-cncf</id>
  <published>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-08T06:20:15-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Presented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://innovate.solarwinds.io&quot;&gt;SolarWinds Innovate Summit 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://calcotestudios.com/talks/decks/slides-innovate-summit-2017-state-of-serverless-the-cncf.html&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;420&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;allowfullscreen&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-mce-type=&quot;bookmark&quot; style=&quot;display: inline-block; width: 0px; overflow: hidden; line-height: 0;&quot; class=&quot;mce_SELRES_start&quot;&gt;﻿&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe title=&quot;The Serverless Landscape &amp;amp; the CNCF - Innovate Summit 2017&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iEdltQgfNLU?feature=oembed&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2017/12/innovate-summit-2017-state-of-serverless-the-cncf/&quot;&gt;Innovate Summit 2017 - State of Serverless &amp; the CNCF&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 08, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Containers and Functions - Leveraging Ephemeral Infrastructure Effectively]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/04/containers-and-functions-leveraging-ephemeral-infrastructure-effectively/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/04/containers-and-functions-leveraging-ephemeral-infrastructure-effectively</id>
  <published>2018-12-03T06:06:15-06:00</published>
  <updated>2018-12-03T06:06:15-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Originally published on Container Journal on December 3rd, 2018.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With containers, microservices and functions interweaving through modern application design, diligence is necessary to make sure you’re successfully navigating when to use containers and functions as application packaging technologies and how to employ post-deployment techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know this can be daunting—it’s an ephemeral world out there. Establishing a delivery pipeline and streamlining workflow for microservices is key to achieving benefits from containers and functions at both an operational level for confidence of resiliency, performance and so on, and at a strategic business level for competitive advantages of speed, flexibility and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore several universal best practices for succeeding in the ephemeral world of containers and functions, and walk through a few of the ins and outs of discerning befitting use of serverless computing. Then, in my next blog post, we’ll look at how to harness the value promised by incorporation of a service mesh into your stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorporating Orchestration: Wrangling Container Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given their near-ubiquitous adoption, container formats and their runtime engines have effectively standardized and stabilized as reliable and interoperable infrastructure. Organizations of all sizes have been running containers in production for a number of years now. Their success in operating containerized workloads in complex ways may be largely attributed to the capabilities of container orchestrators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I described when contrasting and comparing container orchestrators, use of a container orchestrator addresses much of layer of infrastructure needs, it does not meet all application or service-level requirements. Isn’t that why we run infrastructure? To serve the application? With that rhetorical question asked, container orchestrators have necessarily focused first on infrastructure level concerns, critical to ensuring robust management of the underlying substrate of distributed systems challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use of a container orchestrator does not meet all application or service-level requirements. Isn’t that why we run infrastructure? To serve the application? With that rhetorical question asked, container orchestrators have necessarilyfocused first on infrastructure-level concerns, critical to ensuring robust management of the underlying substrate of distributed systems challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this leaves a number of distributed systems concerns for developers to address. Until recently, developers have largely addressed these concerns by writing infrastructure logic into application code—things such as circuit breaking, timeouts and retries—employing client-side libraries to do so. In my second part in this series, I’ll highlight how DevOps teams can manage the layer of challenges unaddressed by container orchestrators using a service mesh. For now, let’s turn our focus to another ephemeral piece of infrastructure—functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Costs and Benefits of Serverless Computing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of you have become comfortable running multiple containers and are now looking to transcend containers and microservices, augmenting your stack by interweaving functions. Writing individual functions to complete specific tasks is appealing, as doing so facilitates faster startup times, better resource utilization, finer-grained management, flexible and precise scaling and no provisioning, updating or managing server infrastructure. However, certain use cases are better-suited for serverless computing than others. Testing, startup latency, debuggability and cost all must be considered when deciding if serverless is the right fit for an environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The notion of running a function to perform a task and only paying for the execution time needed to run that task is veryappealing. As functions take foothold with your applications, exercise caution with respect to serverless pricing models, as cost accumulates quickly. Costs can accrue in short order when either a given function enjoys too much success (is invoked well beyond the number of times initially accounted for), particularly if the execution of one function in turn calls other many functions (or, perhaps, calls back to itself, creating an endless loop of execution). It’s therefore important to understand how many times the function is going to be invoked when deciding if serverless is the right fit. Functions are best-suited for a task that’s run under a short time period. Be conscientious when calling a function from another function: You run the risk of doubling your cost and increasing the complexity of debugging your software as it divides into more and smaller units of independent execution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FaaScinating Use Cases&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The architectural pattern of the use of functions follows an event-driven design, typically persisting output/results from a function to a datastore or queue that in turn triggers the next function (if needed). When ascribing to this pattern, treat all data as though it is in motion, not at rest, at any point during the execution of your function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s best to consider serverless when a workload is: asynchronous; concurrent; easy to parallelize into independent units of work; infrequent or with sporadic demand; with large, unpredictable variance in scaling requirements; stateless; ephemeral; without a major need for instantaneous cold start time; or highly dynamic in terms of changing business requirements that drive a need for accelerated developer velocity. Example workloads that readily benefit from serverless architectures include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Executing logic in response to database changes (insert, update, trigger, delete).
Performing analytics on IoT sensor input messages, for example, as Message Queuing Telemetry Transport (MQTT) messages.
Handling stream processing (analyzing or modifying data in motion).
Managing single time extract, transform, and load jobs that require a great deal of processing for a short time.
Providing cognitive computing via a chat bot interface (asynchronous, but correlated).
Scheduling tasks performed for a short time (e.g., cron or batch style invocations).
Serving machine learning and AI models (retrieving one or more data elements such as tables or images and matching against a pre-learned data model to identify text, faces, anomalies, etc.).
Continuous integration pipelines that provision resources for build jobs on-demand, instead of keeping a pool of build slave hosts waiting for jobs to be dispatched.
Universal Tips for Successfully Navigating an Ephemeral World&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As application packing technologies, both containers and functions have their own caveats, so knowing how and when to leverage them is key. In your organization, you can apply four universally applicable best practices to packaging, running, deploying and operating containers and functions, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritize Observability: When writing an application for containers, particularly in the case of a microservices design, it’s crucial to ensure both your orchestration and application layers are observable to ensure they expose key metrics about the performance of your infrastructure and application, so that you may reason over their health as needed.
Adopt Modern Tooling: Containers, microservices and functions pose different application development patterns than you may have traditionally encountered, so the right tooling is not always available. However, it’s crucial to adopt monitoring and debugging tools that can support these application development patterns, to help ensure success in deployment and running workloads.
Application Design: The modern application development landscape is ephemeral; a function will come and go, a container will come and go, and applications must be designed to support this life cycle. For functions specifically, you can run into issues with incorrect logic and end up having functions fall into a vicious cycle of calling each other, billing spikes and generally not working effectively.
Fit Your Use Case: How many of the characteristics listed above apply to your user case? Is this use case or your application well-positioned for these ephemeral execution environments?
Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first, the idea of running a function to perform a task and only paying for the execution time needed to run that task is attractive. However, this pricing model can become expensive if you are executing many functions or running a specific function millions of times. With that in mind, it’s crucial to understand how many times the function is going to be invoked when deciding if serverless is the right fit—lengthy batch-processing tasks may not be the best fit for use of a function; functions are better-suited for a task that’s run under a short time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As containers, microservices and functions become even more integrated into hybrid and cloud environments, you must remain diligent to ensure you’re navigating these aspects of the modern application development landscape successfully. Implementing several universal best practices including prioritizing observability, adopting modern DevOps monitoring tools, application design and knowing specific use cases can all help you succeed in the world of containers, microservices and functions.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/04/containers-and-functions-leveraging-ephemeral-infrastructure-effectively/&quot;&gt;Containers and Functions - Leveraging Ephemeral Infrastructure Effectively&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 03, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Automation and Orchestration in a Container World]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/09/automation-and-orchestration-in-a-container-world/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/automation-and-orchestration-in-a-container-world</id>
  <published>2018-09-13T07:50:15-05:00</published>
  <updated>2018-09-13T07:50:15-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Automation-Orchestration-Container.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignright wp-image-2199 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Automation-Orchestration-Container-300x129.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;129&quot; srcset=&quot;http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Automation-Orchestration-Container-300x129.jpg 300w, http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Automation-Orchestration-Container-768x329.jpg 768w, http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/09/Automation-Orchestration-Container.jpg 800w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://containerjournal.com/2018/09/17/automation-and-orchestration-in-a-container-world/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Originally published&lt;/a&gt; on Sept. 17th, 2018 on Container Journal.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Docker began popularizing containers about five and a half years ago, this technology has become a key element of digital business transformation. Characteristics such as portability, highly efficient sharing of system resources and broad support have made containers an increasingly popular choice. In fact, in March 2017, a &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.dell.com/sites/doccontent/business/solutions/whitepapers/en/Documents/Containers_Real_Adoption_2017_Dell_EMC_Forrester_Paper.pdf&quot;&gt;Forrester study &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;found 66 percent of organizations that had adopted containers experienced accelerated developer efficiency, while 75 percent of companies achieved a moderate-to-significant increase in application deployment speed.&lt;span id=&quot;more-2196&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These positive impacts are accelerating container adoption; in SolarWinds’ recent “&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.solarwinds.com/company/press-releases/2018-q2/solarwinds-study-of-it-professionals-finds-cloud-computing-is-top-transformative-technology-and-main-cause-of-mounting-performance-challenges&quot;&gt;IT Trends Report 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;,” 44 percent of respondents ranked containers as the most important technology priority today, and 38 percent of respondents ranked containers as the most important technology priority three to five years from now. These industry statistics confirm that container technology interest and adoption is increasing with time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To successfully deploy containers, technology professionals must understand the impact this technology will have on various aspects of the way in which their applications and infrastructure run, and uplevel both their skills and tools accordingly. Even the most nominally sized container deployment calls upon orchestration to help manage new aspects of this technology’s life cycle. With the rapid adoption of containers, container orchestrators saw a sharp rise in popularity as they streamlined management for IT administrators and broadly provided for the general caretaking (e.g., scheduling, service discovery, health checking, etc.) of a cluster of nodes (servers) running containers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying Containers: Impact on the Network and Security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact containers have on various aspects of an IT environment are in part contingent on the type of containerized workload deployed. To understand this better, let’s characterize two classes of containerized workloads being run as either a system container or an application container. System containers can be described as VM-like in nature, and generally contain a full operating system image and run multiple processes, while an application container is often lighterweight both in terms of footprint and number of processes running (ideally, only a single process). Both classes of containers use namespaces to deal with resource isolation and control groups (cgroups) to manage and enforce resource limits. However, the former lends itself to the containerization of pre-existing applications, while the latter is a best practices pattern for applications initially written to be run as a container.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how does this distinction materialize in the administration of IT environments? For example, when a system container is deployed, the network may not be a significant consideration when containerizing an entire system and treating it similarly to a VM. By contrast, using application containers to deploy microservices requires requests and application traffic to transit several containers and hosts over the network—potentially even several different networks—making it crucial to have a network monitoring system in place to track latency and ensure requests are addressed in a timely and effective manner. This is easier said than done; although implementing microservices can allow teams to iterate more quickly, they introduce several different components of an application and can be difficult to monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As with the implementation of any new technology, security must be strongly considered. Vulnerability scanning and runtime protection should be weaved into the security practices of any organization deploying containers. Vulnerability scanning is necessary when various packages and libraries are built into each container, whether those are pulled from open source repositories, from internal code repositories or even if the container images are reused from public container registries. Security scanning must be completed to verify that there are no inherent vulnerabilities within a given image’s layers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether containerizing an entire system or building an application container from scratch, static analysis of an image’s layers and its Dockerfile (a text document that contains all the commands a user could call on the command line to assemble an image) is key to identifying any vulnerabilities. In the second step of maintaining security, after verifying the container images have a clean bill of health and then deploying them, it’s necessary to implement runtime security. Containers can elicit abnormal behavior that could be caused by an administrator not adhering to operational best practices, or a malicious hacker that has penetrated a container. Runtime security helps ensure that once deployed, containers function within their intended bounds of operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, how can technology professionals best manage container technology to reap the maximum benefits of leveraging it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigating Challenges through Automation and Orchestration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leveraging automation and orchestration helps technology professionals save time and money, prevents issues, and ultimately deploys containers in the most effective way possible. Once a container deployment grows beyond a few hosts, technology professionals typically find the operational functionality provided by container orchestrators critical. Orchestrators commonly provide cluster management (host discovery and host health monitoring), scheduling (placement of containers across hosts in the cluster), service discovery (automatic registration of new services and provisioning of friendly DNS names) and so on. Orchestration is key to scaling deployments and to facilitating efficient collaboration between different engineering teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As container implementation becomes more mainstream, clear standards in container technology have begun to emerge, particularly for the foundational components of containers. The &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.opencontainers.org/&quot;&gt;Open Container Initiative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; (OCI), for example, calls for creating open industry standards around runtime and image specifications to ensure vendors are able to guarantee and deliver on the promise of portability, allowing containers to be effectively shipped and interoperable across different systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Various tools and best practices in the realm of automation and orchestration can help facilitate successful container deployment and management. For example, leveraging a configuration management tool such as &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://puppet.com/&quot;&gt;Puppet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; gives technology professionals a way to automatically inspect and deliver their software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, treating infrastructure as code can help companies that are working toward faster deployments, as this method calls for managing the infrastructure with the same tools and processes that software developers use, such as automated testing, continuous integration, code review, and version control. These enable infrastructure changes to be completed more easily, rapidly, safely, and reliably. Understanding the type of (and extent of) management that a given container deployment requires is also essential. In some cases leveraging a solution such as &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.docker.com/&quot;&gt;Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; in swarm mode is sufficient, while others may call for a tool such as &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kubernetes.io/&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Successful Container Management and Deployment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to leveraging automation and orchestration, technology professionals should develop new skills and leverage tools and services when implementing container technology in their organization. Here are a few tips to help facilitate successful container deployment and management:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get certified in third-party tools:&lt;/strong&gt; For NetAdmins, SysAdmins, or those who are “container curious,” getting certified in Docker and Kubernetes can help uplevel container management skills. Whether certification is achieved or not, merely studying the curriculum provides a helpful guide to aspects of container management that a tech pro may be otherwise unaware of.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor as a Discipline (MaaD): &lt;/strong&gt;Companies expect performance guarantees, cost efficiency, and service availability from their IT departments. One effective way to meet these requirements while using container technology is by leveraging monitoring tools. Actively tracking the activity in environments when application traffic is transiting the network is crucial and using a monitoring tool to set up automated alerts can also be beneficial when container deployments fail.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conduct regular vulnerability scan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;s: &lt;/strong&gt;Organizations that choose to work with container technology will need to create a security framework and set of procedures that are consistently evaluated and updated to prevent attacks. Conducting regular scans of container images is key, as it provides visibility into their security, including vulnerabilities, malware, and policy violations. Even prominently and popularly used container images on public-facing container repositories are subject to being laced with vulnerabilities. Many container-related security vendors such as &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.twistlock.com/&quot;&gt;Twistlock&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; and container registries offer help to identify issues introduced by these vulnerabilities. Container orchestration systems and container runtimes enable regular health-checks by probing the software inside containers to ensure that the application is still healthy and functional.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Words of Encouragement: Skill Up and Fear Not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With container use increasingly becoming mainstream, it’s important for technology professionals to embrace them now, and avoid letting containers happen to them. But fear not—for tech pros hesitant to implement this new technology, containers are not as foreign or intimidating as they seem. While distinct from virtual machines, administrators familiar with VM management will find many of these paradigms reincarnated. To get started, administrators can even experiment with containers by leveraging the technology on their personal laptops.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing automation tooling and orchestration can enhance strategies and tactics to enable smooth container use and adoption, and several additional best practices can help ensure successful implementation and deployment. Beyond automation and orchestration, technology professionals without a background in software engineering should also look to learn scripting, as it will serve them well as deployments scale. Practice building efficient container images, using multi-stage builds, and sorting multi-line arguments alphanumerically is also key. Docker even offers &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.docker.com/develop/develop-images/dockerfile_best-practices/&quot;&gt;best practices and methods&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; for building container images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, as emerging technologies with higher-level capabilities such as functions and serverless platforms, service meshes, analytics, and machine learning are poised to augment container technology in the coming years, it’s important for administrators to skill up now more than ever.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/09/automation-and-orchestration-in-a-container-world/&quot;&gt;Automation and Orchestration in a Container World&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on September 13, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Now Available - The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/08/now-available-the-enterprise-path-to-service-mesh-architectures/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/08/now-available-the-enterprise-path-to-service-mesh-architectures</id>
  <published>2018-09-08T07:25:15-05:00</published>
  <updated>2018-09-08T07:25:15-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nginx.com/resources/library/the-enterprise-path-to-service-mesh-architectures?utm_source=calcote&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-medium wp-image-2089&quot; src=&quot;https://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/The-Enterprise-Path-to-Service-Mesh-Architectures-200x300.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; srcset=&quot;http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/The-Enterprise-Path-to-Service-Mesh-Architectures-200x300.png 200w, http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/The-Enterprise-Path-to-Service-Mesh-Architectures-768x1152.png 768w, http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/08/The-Enterprise-Path-to-Service-Mesh-Architectures-683x1024.png 683w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 200px) 100vw, 200px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;As someone interested in modern software design, you have likely heard of service mesh architectures in context of microservices. Service meshes introduce a new layer into modern infrastructures, offering the potential for creating robust and scalable applications and granular control over them. Is a service mesh right for you?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My newly published short book,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://learning.oreilly.com/library/view/the-enterprise-path/9781492041795/?utm_source=calcote&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, helps answer common questions on service mesh architectures through the lens of a large enterprise and addresses how to evaluate your organization’s readiness, factors to consider when building new applications and converting existing applications to best leverage a service mesh, and offers insight on deployment architectures used to get you there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;#8217;t the only O&amp;#8217;Reilly title available on the topic of service meshes, however. Before authoring&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;I happily provided technical review of two other excellent O’Reilly titles on the topic of service meshes: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/christianposta&quot;&gt;Christian Posta&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/burrsutter&quot;&gt;Burr Sutter&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.christianposta.com/our-book-has-been-released-introducing-istio-service-mesh-for-microservices?utm_source=calcote&quot;&gt;Introducing Istio Service Mesh for Microservices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/gmiranda23&quot;&gt;George Miranda&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216;s &lt;em&gt;The Service Mesh&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;span id=&quot;more-2079&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;These three complement each other well, helping educate adopters and onlookers alike:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Introducing Istio Service Mesh for Microservices&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Christian Posta and George Miranda does an excellent job of introducing Istio, specifically, and walks through examples of each of its core capabilities. Their book provides a unique perspective of Istio through ever so faintly-tinted OpenShift lens. The code samples incorporated to the book are clear and helpful in quickly ramping on Istio.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Service Mesh&lt;/i&gt; by George Miranda is an introduction to service meshes in general and successfully avoids the natural inclination to compare specifics between popular service mesh offerings. Instead, George gives real-world examples of where and how service meshes have benefited customers. There’s clear value derived in learning from George&amp;#8217;s experience.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;&quot; style=&quot;padding-left: 30px;&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;The Enterprise Path to&amp;nbsp;Service Mesh Architectures&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;by Lee Calcote focuses on the value of service meshes, how they contrast against container orchestrators and other microservices frameworks, what shape various deployment models take, customization and integration of service meshes into existing infrastructure.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For as well as these three short books cover the space and specific technologies, much room is left for a deeper, post-Istio-1.0 book. And its exactly such a book that I and my two coauthors, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/baldwinmathew&quot;&gt;Matt Baldwin&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/zackbutcher?lang=en&quot;&gt;Zack Butcher&lt;/a&gt;, have set forth to produce:&amp;nbsp;&lt;i class=&quot;&quot;&gt;Istio: Up and Running&lt;/i&gt;. There’s clear underlap and complement in these short books and our forthcoming title.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;Like other titles on emergent technology, there’s risk in a short shelf-live of some of the technical content. The post-1.0 publication of &lt;em&gt;Istio: Up and Running&lt;/em&gt; certainly improves the&amp;nbsp;durability of its content. To further its usefulness (and shelf-life), we&amp;#8217;re deemphasizing specifics of Istio&amp;#8217;s deployment and focusing on other aspects like advanced deployment, multi-cluster, multi-tenant, best practices, case studies, etc., lacing these with code samples throughout.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gingergeek.com&quot;&gt;my blog&lt;/a&gt; or sign-up below for updates &amp;#8211;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;link href=&quot;//cdn-images.mailchimp.com/embedcode/classic-10_7.css&quot; rel=&quot;stylesheet&quot; type=&quot;text/css&quot; /&gt;
&lt;style type=&quot;text/css&quot;&gt;
	#mc_embed_signup{background:#fff; clear:left; font:14px Helvetica,Arial,sans-serif; }&lt;br /&gt;
	/* Add your own Mailchimp form style overrides in your site stylesheet or in this style block.&lt;br /&gt;
	   We recommend moving this block and the preceding CSS link to the HEAD of your HTML file. */&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup&quot;&gt;
&lt;form action=&quot;https://calcotestudios.us15.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=6b50be5aea3dfe1fd4c041d80&amp;amp;id=6bb65defeb&quot; method=&quot;post&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; name=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe-form&quot; class=&quot;validate&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; novalidate=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mc_embed_signup_scroll&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;indicates-required&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;asterisk&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; indicates required&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mc-field-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot;&gt;Email Address &lt;span class=&quot;asterisk&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/label&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;email&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;EMAIL&quot; class=&quot;required email&quot; id=&quot;mce-EMAIL&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mc-field-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;mce-FNAME&quot;&gt;First Name &lt;/label&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;FNAME&quot; class=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;mce-FNAME&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;mc-field-group&quot;&gt;
&lt;label for=&quot;mce-LNAME&quot;&gt;Last Name &lt;/label&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; value=&quot;&quot; name=&quot;LNAME&quot; class=&quot;&quot; id=&quot;mce-LNAME&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;mce-responses&quot; class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;response&quot; id=&quot;mce-error-response&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;response&quot; id=&quot;mce-success-response&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;position: absolute; left: -5000px;&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;text&quot; name=&quot;b_6b50be5aea3dfe1fd4c041d80_6bb65defeb&quot; tabindex=&quot;-1&quot; value=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;clear&quot;&gt;&lt;input type=&quot;submit&quot; value=&quot;Subscribe&quot; name=&quot;subscribe&quot; id=&quot;mc-embedded-subscribe&quot; class=&quot;button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/08/now-available-the-enterprise-path-to-service-mesh-architectures/&quot;&gt;Now Available - The Enterprise Path to Service Mesh Architectures&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on September 08, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to customize an Istio Service Mesh]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2018/05/how-to-customize-an-istio-service-mesh/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/how-to-customize-an-istio-service-mesh</id>
  <published>2018-05-09T08:20:15-05:00</published>
  <updated>2018-05-09T08:20:15-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/louvre-pyramid-mesh-perspective-2189967/&quot;&gt;&lt;img aria-describedby=&quot;caption-attachment-2050&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-2050 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/louvre-2189967_crop-98f00246a2776bae3338fdcb88b2badf-300x200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; srcset=&quot;http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/louvre-2189967_crop-98f00246a2776bae3338fdcb88b2badf-300x200.jpg 300w, http://gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/louvre-2189967_crop-98f00246a2776bae3338fdcb88b2badf.jpg 720w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;lt;p id=&quot;caption-attachment-2050&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&amp;gt;Louvre mesh perspective (source: jraffin via Pixabay)&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/ideas/how-to-customize-an-istio-service-mesh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Originally published&lt;/a&gt; on April 26th, 2018 on O’Reilly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though service meshes provide value outside of the use of microservices and containers, it&amp;#8217;s in these environments that many teams first consider using a service mesh. The sheer volume of services that must be managed on an individual, distributed basis with microservices (versus centrally for a monolith) creates challenges for ensuring reliability, observability, and security of these services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adoption of a container orchestrator addresses a layer of infrastructure needs, but leaves some application or service-level needs unmet. Rather than attempting to overcome distributed systems concerns by writing infrastructure logic into application code, some teams choose to manage these challenges with a service mesh. A service mesh can help by ensuring the responsibility of service management is centralized, avoiding redundant instrumentation, and making observability ubiquitous and uniform across services.&lt;span id=&quot;more-2049&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Choosing a service mesh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Factors such as your teams’ operational and technology expertise, existing observability, and access control tooling will influence the service mesh components, adapters, and deployment model you choose. Among others, Istio is a popularly adopted, open source service mesh. Some choose Istio (or any service mesh) for the automatic and immediate visibility it provides into top-line service metrics. In fact, many become hooked on service meshes for the observability they provide alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a microservices platform, Istio is extensible through the way in which it offers choice of adapters and sidecars. Istio envelops and integrates with other open source projects to deliver a full-service mesh, which both bolsters its set of capabilities and offers a choice of which specific projects are included and deployed. Whether through Mixer adapters for observability or through swapping sidecars, Istio allows you to choose which components to include in your deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Customizing an Istio service mesh&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are multiple deployment models you can use to lay down a service mesh. One of the most popular options is to deploy your service proxies as sidecars. Sidecarring your service proxy offers benefits like fine-grained policy enforcement and intra-cluster service-to-service encryption. This deployment model is the model of choice for Istio. Other Istio deployment choices include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mixer adapters: typically used for integrating with access control, telemetry, quota enforcement, and billing systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service proxies: abstract the network, translating requests between a client and service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though Envoy is the default service proxy sidecar, you may choose another service proxy for your sidecar. While there are multiple service proxies in the ecosystem, outside of Envoy, only two have currently demonstrated integration with Istio: Linkerd and NGINX. The arrival of choice in service proxies for Istio has generated a lot of excitement. &lt;a href=&quot;https://linkerd.io/getting-started/istio/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;Linkerd’s integration&lt;/a&gt; was created early in Istio’s 0.1.6 release. Similarly, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/nginmesh/nginmesh&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;nginMesh&lt;/a&gt; project has drawn much interest in the use of NGINX as Istio’s service proxy, as many organizations have broad and deep operational expertise built around this battle-tested proxy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Learn more about how to deploy your sidecar (Istio proxy) of choice in the free webcast &amp;#8220;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/pub/e/3926?intcmp=il-data-webcast-lp-webcast_new_site_how-to-customize-an-istio-service-mesh_end_body_link_cta&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Istio &amp;#8211; The extensible service mesh&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8220;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2018/05/how-to-customize-an-istio-service-mesh/&quot;&gt;How to customize an Istio Service Mesh&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Hybrid Evolution of IT]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/the-hybrid-evolution-of-it/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/the-hybrid-evolution-of-it</id>
  <published>2017-04-25T16:01:00-05:00</published>
  <updated>2017-04-25T16:01:00-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;“It’s a great time to be in Information Technology.” While this is a true statement, not everyone clearly understands why (or perhaps, has the fortitude to make it so). In the face of a massive movement to public cloud—by 2020, 92% of world’s workloads will be in cloud—68% in public and 32% in private&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/solutions/collateral/service-provider/global-cloud-index-gci/white-paper-c11-738085.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;—many in IT feel their value in the workplace eroding along with their identity. This feeling doesn’t need to be reality. Businesses are changing the way they operate and are transforming to leverage information technology more strategically. IT has a real opportunity to &lt;em&gt;lead&lt;/em&gt; this transformation, not let the transformation &lt;em&gt;happen to them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT has led digital transformations before and can do it again. About ten years ago, the video security surveillance industry underwent a digital transformation wherein video security systems transitioned from coaxial cable networks to IP-based Ethernet, from analog video on tape to digitally-encoded video on disk, and from physically separate networks to consolidating into IT-run data centers. IT was the digital leader here, bringing many improvements to the way in which physical security functions. At the end of the day, the physical security guard remained, and in combination with their IT partners, delivered on their charter more efficiently than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IT has an opportunity to drive digital transformation again, particularly as many businesses are changing the way they operate. Concerned with disrupting or being disrupted, many businesses are pivoting to become software companies. Yes, software is eating the world. As I arrive to the SolarWinds corporate headquarters each work day, I’m reminded of that fact by literal example—AMD, a leading chip designer, has shrunk its operations to share it campus with SolarWinds, a global software company. As businesses shift, CIOs are poised to help IT switch from a cost center to a source of differentiated value in terms of how a business might differentiate from other players in their industry. CIOs are positioned to be in a highly strategic, visible, and collaborative position within the company. A recent Harvard Business Review study&lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/pdfs/comm/RedHat/RedHatReportMay2015.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; shows that while nearly half of lines-of-business leader respondents said they would like to learn more about digital trends from their CIO, unfortunately, close to two-fifths said their CIO does not seek to educate and empower line-of-business leaders when it comes to all things digital. Over a third of the organizations polled said IT does not provide useful knowledge about technology or understand which digital knowledge is important to specific business functions. Expectations of CIOs are changing and it behooves IT to rise to the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The white knuckles of IT needs to relax their grip and embrace internal customers as their lifeline, not shun those running shadow IT—be an accelerator, not an inhibitor. Understand that &lt;em&gt;convenience&lt;/em&gt; drives retail consumer purchasing behavior more so than price does. Considering those same individuals bring their consumer behaviors (convenience = &lt;em&gt;agility&lt;/em&gt;) to the workplace, it’s no wonder shadow IT is prevalent and always lurking. IT needs to develop holistic strategies in alignment with the business mission. IT organizations that are digital leaders don’t just let hybrid &lt;em&gt;happen to them&lt;/em&gt;. Digital leaders are three times more likely than to have a comprehensive, enterprise-wide strategy for hybrid cloud&lt;a href=&quot;http://www-01.ibm.com/common/ssi/cgi-bin/ssialias?htmlfid=GMW14087USEN&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hybrid IT strategies may include outsourcing commodity functions. IT can be the provider &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the trusted broker by enabling lines of business with application support, cloud design, not necessarily equipment. A foremost focus on empowerment of the business mission—whether sourcing or providing—is how businesses will leverage IT to renovate I&amp;amp;O and innovate. In some cases, that strategy may involve factions of IT reporting into different LOBs (e.g. marketing and finance). Strategies of hybrid IT organizations embracing public and private cloud are evolving from infrastructure-centric thinking to application-centric thinking, recognizing that operations automation is friend, not foe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing a strategy is not without challenge. Less than a third of the IT organizations polled in a recent SolarWinds&lt;a href=&quot;http://it-trends.solarwinds.com&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt; study consider that they have adequate resources to manage hybrid IT environments. &lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter wp-image-1805 size-full&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/solarwinds-study.png?resize=703%2C282&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-id=&quot;1805&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/solarwinds-study.png?w=703 703w, https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/solarwinds-study.png?resize=300%2C120 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 703px) 100vw, 703px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;Fortunately, any business can excel at digital leadership and management, regardless of its size or budget. Strategies may consider aggressively retiring legacy technology where the application and business case allow. Often it’s not technology impeding implementation of strategy, but people and process. CIOs can mitigate inhibitors from evolving into a hybrid IT organization by helping their people to set aside fear, insecurity, and politics. CIOs need to help individuals within their organization to understand their changing jobs, migrate to new roles, and how to be champions of change in their organizations while continuing to ensure security and continuity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital transformation of today is a hybrid evolution of IT. The broad-sweeping influence technology has on how businesses operate continues to accelerate and leaves no industry untouched. Organizations are learning how to become software companies. Established businesses are being turned upside-down and inside-out as new players have a software-centric view of the world. Current market dynamics are fundamentally changing the relationship businesses have with their IT organization and IT must evolve as business leaders need IT more than ever. It’s an exciting future ahead and &lt;em&gt;a great time to be in information technology&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cisco.com/c/dam/en/us/solutions/collateral/service-provider/global-cloud-index-gci/white-paper-c11-738085.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[1]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;_Cisco Global Cloud Index: Forecast and Methodology, 2015–2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;a href=&quot;https://hbr.org/resources/pdfs/comm/RedHat/RedHatReportMay2015.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[2]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;_Driving Digital Transformation: New Skills for Leaders, New role for the CIO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;gt;http://www-01.ibm.com/common/ssi/cgi-bin/ssialias?htmlfid=GMW14087USEN&quot; name=&quot;_ftn3&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[3]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;_Growing up hybrid: Accelerating digital transformation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_ &lt;a href=&quot;http://opennetworkingusergroup.com/the-hybrid-evolution-of-it/#_ftnref4&quot; name=&quot;_ftn4&quot;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[4]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;IT Trends Report 2016: The Hybrid IT Evolution&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2017/04/the-hybrid-evolution-of-it/&quot;&gt;The Hybrid Evolution of IT&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on April 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Understanding and Extending Prometheus AlertManager]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2017/04/understanding-and-extending-prometheus-alertmanager/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/understanding-and-extending-prometheus-alertmanager</id>
  <published>2017-04-25T15:34:08-05:00</published>
  <updated>2017-04-25T15:34:08-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jpb6fLQOgn4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudnativeeu2017.sched.com/event/9Td7?iframe=no&quot;&gt;CloudNativeCon + KubeCon EU 2017&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tutorial – &lt;a href=&quot;https://thenewstack.io/contributing-prometheus-history-alertmanager/&quot;&gt;Contributing to Prometheus: An Open Source Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sample code – &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/leecalcote/alertmanager/&quot;&gt;leecalcote/alertmanager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slide &lt;a href=&quot;http://calcotestudios.com/kubecon-alertmanager&quot;&gt;deck&lt;/a&gt;{.deck}&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/jpb6fLQOgn4&quot;&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;{.deck}&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2017/04/understanding-and-extending-prometheus-alertmanager/&quot;&gt;Understanding and Extending Prometheus AlertManager&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on April 25, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Create Great CNCF User-Base from Lessons Learned from Other Open Source Communities]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/create-great-cncf-user-base-from-lessons-learned-from-other-open-source-communities/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/create-great-cncf-user-base-from-lessons-learned-from-other-open-source-communities</id>
  <published>2017-03-30T23:55:15-05:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-30T23:55:15-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt; Presented at &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloudnativeeu2017.sched.com/event/9Tc3?iframe=no&quot;&gt;CloudNativeCon + KubeCon EU 2017&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2017/03/create-great-cncf-user-base-from-lessons-learned-from-other-open-source-communities/&quot;&gt;Create Great CNCF User-Base from Lessons Learned from Other Open Source Communities&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on March 30, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Developer-defined application delivery]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/2017/03/developer-defined-application-delivery/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/developer-defined-application-delivery</id>
  <published>2017-03-11T05:17:09-06:00</published>
  <updated>2017-03-11T05:17:09-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;div id=&quot;attachment_1741&quot; style=&quot;width: 310px&quot; class=&quot;wp-caption alignleft&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-1741 size-medium&quot; src=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?resize=300%2C225&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; data-id=&quot;1741&quot; srcset=&quot;https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?resize=300%2C225 300w, https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?resize=768%2C576 768w, https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?resize=1024%2C768 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?w=2000 2000w, https://i0.wp.com/gingergeek.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/03/ship-84139.jpg?w=3000 3000w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px&quot; data-recalc-dims=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&quot;wp-caption-text&quot;&gt;
    Ship with tug (source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://pixabay.com/en/ship-containers-products-shipping-84139/&quot;&gt;tpsdave via Pixabay&lt;/a&gt;).
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud-native applications are designed to draw upon the performance, scalability, and reliability benefits of distributed systems. Unfortunately, distributed systems often come at the cost of added complexity. As individual components of your application are distributed across networks, and those networks have communication gaps or experience degraded performance, your distributed application components need to continue to function independently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To avoid inconsistencies in application state, distributed systems should be designed with an understanding that components will fail. Nowhere is this more prominent than in the network. Consequently, at their core, distributed systems rely heavily on load balancing—the distribution of requests across two or more systems—in order to be resilient in the face of network disruption and horizontally scale as system load fluctuates.&lt;!--more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As distributed systems become more and more prevalent in the design and delivery of cloud-native applications, load balancers saturate infrastructure design at every level of modern application architecture. In their most commonly thought-of configuration, load balancers are deployed in front of the application, handling requests from the outside world. However, the emergence of microservices means that load balancers play a critical role behind the scenes: i.e. managing the flow between services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, when you work with cloud-native applications and distributed systems, your load balancer takes on other role(s):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Read the full article on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/learning/developer-defined-application-delivery&quot;&gt;O’Reilly&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/2017/03/developer-defined-application-delivery/&quot;&gt;Developer-defined application delivery&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on March 11, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sample Post]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/intro/sample-post/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/intro/sample-post</id>
  <updated>2016-12-02T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-12-02T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Below is just about everything you’ll need to style in the theme. Check the source code to see the many embedded elements within paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;heading-1&quot;&gt;Heading 1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading-2&quot;&gt;Heading 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;heading-3&quot;&gt;Heading 3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;heading-4&quot;&gt;Heading 4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;heading-5&quot;&gt;Heading 5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;heading-6&quot;&gt;Heading 6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;body-text&quot;&gt;Body text&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, test link adipiscing elit. &lt;strong&gt;This is strong&lt;/strong&gt;. Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-right&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/3953273590_704e3899d5_m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Smithsonian Image&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is emphasized&lt;/em&gt;. Donec faucibus. Nunc iaculis suscipit dui. 53 = 125. Water is H&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt;O. Nam sit amet sem. Aliquam libero nisi, imperdiet at, tincidunt nec, gravida vehicula, nisl. The New York Times &lt;cite&gt;(That’s a citation)&lt;/cite&gt;. &lt;u&gt;Underline&lt;/u&gt;. Maecenas ornare tortor. Donec sed tellus eget sapien fringilla nonummy. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML and &lt;abbr title=&quot;cascading stylesheets&quot;&gt;CSS&lt;abbr&gt; are our tools. Mauris a ante. Suspendisse quam sem, consequat at, commodo vitae, feugiat in, nunc. Morbi imperdiet augue quis tellus. Praesent mattis, massa quis luctus fermentum, turpis mi volutpat justo, eu volutpat enim diam eget metus.&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/abbr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to show just a part of your post in the come page, add the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- more --&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag to your post content. Everything after this tag will be hidden from the page listing page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blockquotes&quot;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, test link adipiscing elit. Nullam dignissim convallis est. Quisque aliquam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;list-types&quot;&gt;List Types&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ordered-lists&quot;&gt;Ordered Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item one
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;sub item one&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;sub item two&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;sub item three&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item two&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;unordered-lists&quot;&gt;Unordered Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item one&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item two&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Item three&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tables&quot;&gt;Tables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Header1&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Header2&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Header3&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;cell1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;cell2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;cell3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;cell4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;cell5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;cell6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;cell1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;cell2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;cell3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;cell4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;cell5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;cell6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  &lt;tfoot&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Foot1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Foot2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;Foot3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tfoot&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;code-snippets&quot;&gt;Code Snippets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting via Pygments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#container&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-240px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Non Pygments code example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;div id=&quot;awesome&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;p&amp;gt;This is great isn't it?&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buttons&quot;&gt;Buttons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make any link standout more when applying the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.btn&lt;/code&gt; class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;#&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn btn-success&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Success Button&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot;&gt;Primary Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-success&quot;&gt;Success Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-warning&quot;&gt;Warning Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-danger&quot;&gt;Danger Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#&quot; class=&quot;btn btn-info&quot;&gt;Info Button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-featured-image&quot;&gt;Post Featured Image&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To show an image banner at top of your post, use add the following code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;feature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;name of the image&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;credit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;source of the image - optional&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;creditlink&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;source of the image (url) - optional&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The image must be in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/images&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/intro/sample-post/&quot;&gt;Sample Post&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 02, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Syntax Highlighting Post]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/intro/code-highlighting-post/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/intro/code-highlighting-post</id>
  <updated>2016-12-01T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2016-12-01T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Syntax highlighting is a feature that displays source code, in different colors and fonts according to the category of terms. This feature facilitates writing in a structured language such as a programming language or a markup language as both structures and syntax errors are visually distinct. Highlighting does not affect the meaning of the text itself; it is intended only for human readers.&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-noteref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot; rel=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rouge-code-blocks&quot;&gt;Rouge Code Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To modify styling and highlight colors edit &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/_sass/_rouge.scss&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;#container&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;float&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;margin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;-240px&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;width&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;m&quot;&gt;100%&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;nav&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;pagination&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;role=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;navigation&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% if page.previous %}
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.previous.url }}&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;title=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{ page.previous.title }}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Previous article&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% endif %}
    {% if page.next %}
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.next.url }}&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;btn&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;title=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;{{ page.next.title }}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Next article&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    {% endif %}
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- /.pagination --&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;module&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nc&quot;&gt;TagIndex&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;Page&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;initialize&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@site&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@base&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@dir&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;dir&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'index.html'&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;vi&quot;&gt;@name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;read_yaml&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;no&quot;&gt;File&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;base&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'_layouts'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'tag_index.html'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'tag'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag_title_prefix&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'tag_title_prefix'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tagged: '&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag_title_suffix&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;site&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;config&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'tag_title_suffix'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'&amp;amp;#8211;'&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'title'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag_title_prefix&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;self&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'description'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;An archive of posts tagged &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;tag&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;.&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;standard-code-block&quot;&gt;Standard Code Block&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;nav class=&quot;pagination&quot; role=&quot;navigation&quot;&amp;gt;
    {% if page.previous %}
        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.previous.url }}&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; title=&quot;{{ page.previous.title }}&quot;&amp;gt;Previous article&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    {% endif %}
    {% if page.next %}
        &amp;lt;a href=&quot;{{ site.url }}{{ page.next.url }}&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot; title=&quot;{{ page.next.title }}&quot;&amp;gt;Next article&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;
    {% endif %}
&amp;lt;/nav&amp;gt;&amp;lt;!-- /.pagination --&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot; role=&quot;doc-endnote&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax_highlighting&quot;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Syntax_highlighting&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot; role=&quot;doc-backlink&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/intro/code-highlighting-post/&quot;&gt;Syntax Highlighting Post&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on December 01, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dark Post]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/dark-post/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/dark-post</id>
  <published>2016-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This is a sample post to show the dark post theme. To use this dark theme, just add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;    &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;layout&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;dark-post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;on your post. This theme adds a dark background with a white panel to show your content.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/dark-post/&quot;&gt;Dark Post&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on November 30, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Post with a Background Image]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/image/background-image/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/image/background-image</id>
  <published>2016-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Here be a sample post with a custom background image. To utilize this “feature” just add the following YAML to a post’s front matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-yaml&quot; data-lang=&quot;yaml&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;background&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;pi&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;filename.png&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This little bit of YAML makes the assumption that your background image asset is in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;/images&lt;/code&gt; folder. If you place it somewhere else or are hotlinking from the web, just include the full http(s):// URL. Either way you should have a background image that is tiled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to set a background image for the entire site just add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;background: filename.png&lt;/code&gt; to your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; and BOOM — background images on every page!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div xmlns:cc=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/ns#&quot; xmlns:dct=&quot;http://purl.org/dc/terms/&quot; about=&quot;http://subtlepatterns.com&quot; class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;Background images from &lt;span property=&quot;dct:title&quot;&gt;Subtle Patterns&lt;/span&gt; (&lt;a rel=&quot;cc:attributionURL&quot; property=&quot;cc:attributionName&quot; href=&quot;http://subtlepatterns.com&quot;&gt;Subtle Patterns&lt;/a&gt;) / &lt;a rel=&quot;license&quot; href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/&quot;&gt;CC BY-SA 3.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/image/background-image/&quot;&gt;Post with a Background Image&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on November 29, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sample Link Post]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://aronbordin.com" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/intro/sample-link-post</id>
  <published>2016-11-28T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This theme supports &lt;strong&gt;link posts&lt;/strong&gt;, made famous by John Gruber. To use, just add &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;link: http://url-you-want-linked&lt;/code&gt; to the post’s YAML front matter and you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/intro/sample-link-post/&quot;&gt;Sample Link Post&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on November 28, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Post with a Video]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/intro/video-post/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/intro/video-post</id>
  <published>2016-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/SU3kYxJmWuQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Video embeds are responsive and scale with the width of the main content block with the help of &lt;a href=&quot;http://fitvidsjs.com/&quot;&gt;FitVids&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding YouTube video embeds causes errors when building your Jekyll site. To fix wrap the html within &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;{::nomarkdown}&lt;/code&gt; tags. Example below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;{::nomarkdown}
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;iframe&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;width=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;560&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;height=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;315&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/SU3kYxJmWuQ&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;frameborder=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;0&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;allowfullscreen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/iframe&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
{:/nomarkdown}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/intro/video-post/&quot;&gt;A Post with a Video&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on November 27, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Post with Images]]></title>
 <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/sample/intro/sample-post-images/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/sample/intro/sample-post-images</id>
  <published>2016-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</published>
  <updated>2016-11-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Lee Calcote</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>lee@calcotestudios.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;Here are some examples of what a post with images might look like. If you want to display two or three images next to each other responsively use &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; with the appropriate &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;. Each instance of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figure&lt;/code&gt; is auto-numbered and displayed in the caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;figures-for-images-or-video&quot;&gt;Figures (for images or video)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-up&quot;&gt;One Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_b.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/80901381@N04/7758832526/&quot; title=&quot;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&quot;&gt;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;one-center&quot;&gt;One Center&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half center&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_b.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8426/7758832526_cc8f681e48_c.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.flickr.com/photos/80901381@N04/7758832526/&quot; title=&quot;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&quot;&gt;Morning Fog Emerging From Trees by A Guy Taking Pictures, on Flickr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;two-up&quot;&gt;Two Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;half&lt;/code&gt; class like so to display two images side by side that share the same caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figure&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;half&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/images/image-filename-1.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;/images/image-filename-2.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Caption describing these two images.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’ll get something that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;half&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Two images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;three-up&quot;&gt;Three Up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;third&lt;/code&gt; class like so to display three images side by side that share the same caption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figure&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;third&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;src=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;alt=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
	&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Caption describing these three images.&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figcaption&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/figure&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And you’ll get something that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://placehold.it/1200x600.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://placehold.it/600x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Three images.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;alternative-way&quot;&gt;Alternative way&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another way to achieve the same result is to include &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;gallery&lt;/code&gt; Liquid template. In this case you
don’t have to write any HTML tags – just copy a small block of code, adjust the parameters (see below)
and fill the block with any number of links to images. You can mix relative and external links.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the block you might want to use:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jinja&quot; data-lang=&quot;jinja&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;capture&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
	/images/abstract-10.jpg
	/images/abstract-11.jpg
	http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/24/Lenna.png
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;endcapture&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;{%&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;gallery&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;images&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;caption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Test images&quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;cols&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;%}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;caption&lt;/code&gt;: Sets the caption under the gallery (see &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;figcaption&lt;/code&gt; HTML tag above);&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cols&lt;/code&gt;: Sets the number of columns of the gallery.
Available values: [1..3].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It will look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;third&quot;&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/abstract-10.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/abstract-10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;/images/abstract-11.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/abstract-11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/24/Lenna.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/2/24/Lenna.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    
    &lt;figcaption&gt;Test images&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/sample/intro/sample-post-images/&quot;&gt;A Post with Images&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Lee Calcote at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Ginger Geek&lt;/a&gt; on November 26, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>
